He's got a good future if he can live past next week.
Carlito's Way is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Brian De Palma.
Free after years in prison, Carlito Brigante intends to give up his criminal ways, but it's
not long before the ex-con is sucked back into the New York City underworld.
Carlito Brigante, played by Al Pacino.
David Kleinfeld, played by Sean Penn.
Gail, played by Penelope Ann Miller.
Benny Blanco, played by John Leguizamo.
Steffie, played by Ingrid Rogers.
Pachanga, played by Luis Guzmán.
Carlito's Way is a 1993 American crime drama film directed by Brian De Palma and written by David Koepp,
based on the novels Carlito's Way (1975) and After Hours (1979) by Judge Edwin Torres.
It stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzman, John
Leguizamo, Jorge Porcel, Joseph Siravo and Viggo Mortensen.
Pacino portrays Carlito Brigante, a Nuyorican criminal who
vows to go straight and to retire in Paradise.
However, his criminal past proves difficult to escape, and he is unwillingly dragged
into the same activities that got him imprisoned in the first place.
The film is based mainly on After Hours, but it used the title of the first
novel to avoid it being confused with Martin Scorsese's 1985 film.
This is the second film collaboration with Pacino
and De Palma, after Scarface (1983).
Carlito's Way was released on November 12, 1993, by Universal Pictures.
It initially received mixed reviews from critics and lukewarm results at the box office,
although general reception to the film has improved in subsequent years.
The film has gained a strong cult following, and it is generally
considered to be one of De Palma's most enduring films.
Both Penn and Miller received Golden Globe nominations for their performances.
A prequel titled Carlito's Way: Rise to Power, based on the
first novel, was released direct-to-video in 2005.
The film explores themes of new york city, based on novel or
book, gangster, go-go dancer, release from prison.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.